Guide to the Juan Felipe Herrera Papers, ca. 1970-1998 M1043
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Juan Felipe Herrera Papers
circa 1970-1998
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Herrera, Juan Felipe
M1043
42 Linear Feet
Manuscripts and other original work, correspondence (mainly incoming), works by other writers and artists (primarily Chicano).
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Herrera's collection bridges nearly thirty years of his literary career, as well as memorabilia from his childhood and high school years. The collection is divided into seven series, several of which are further divided into subseries and subsubseries. The first series includes mostly incoming Correspondence from well over three hundred writers, artists, friends, and others. The second series, Manuscripts, Journals, and Other Literary Material, contains drafts, notes, sketches, and journal entries spanning the years 1972 through 1998. Arranged in three subseries, manuscript material for many of Herrera's poems, essays, and books appears in the first, while the second subseries is dedicated exclusively to the manuscript development of Mayan Drifter. The third subseries holds journals, notebooks, planners, appointment and phone books with handwritten entries dating from 1977 through 1998. Series 3: Educational Career and Teaching Materials, is further divided into four subseries, covering Herrera's years in the Stanford graduate anthropology program, various workshops and conferences including the Creative Writing workshop at the University of Iowa, syllabi, course materials, and student papers and projects from his classes at CSU-Fresno, and material from his visits to high schools, elementary schools, and workshops with inmates in California correctional facilities. Manuscripts, sketches, chapbooks, student papers, submissions for publication, and other material from over thirty poets, friends, acquaintances, are found in Series 4: Manuscripts and Literary Works by Others, including work by Francisco X. Alarcon, Lauro Flores, Margarita Luna Robles, and Victor Martinez. Series 5: Personal and Legal Papers, Miscellaneous Material gathers a range of materials into five subseries, covering: family documents; legal papers regarding a literary lawsuit directly involving Herrera and a murder trial peripherally involving his friend Francisco Alarcon; award announcements and newspaper articles concerning Herrera or acquaintances; flyers, handbills, and other types of announcements regarding poetry readings or appearances by Herrera; and similar material regarding appearances by friends and acquaintances of Herrera. The Photographs and Slides found in Series 6 are broken into two subseries, the first featuring: images of Herrera's involvement with mural projects in San Diego; various theatre groups and poetry readings; items submitted for publications edited by Herrera; pictures of Herrera and friends, covering the time period between the early 1970s to 1998. Also in this subseries can be found a photograph of his uncles in Texas during the 1920s. The second subseries contains photographs and slides of Herrera's 1970 trip to Mexico, with a few images from a later visit in 1993. Audio-Visual Materials are found in Series 7, and contain audio tapes, both four-track cassette and reel to reel, and visual media consisting of video cassettes in various formats, and film in 8 mm and 16 mm widths. The material recorded in this series includes: interviews with poets and artists; performances of theatre groups associated with Herrera; video productions featuring Herrera or produced by friends; sound and visual from Herrera's 1970 trip to Mexico; and various recordings of student projects.
Biography
Juan Felipe Herrera is the son of Mexican migrant workers and is an accomplished writer who has been honored with National Endowment for the Arts grants (1980, 1985), the American Book Award (1987), four California Arts Council grants, the UC Berkeley Regent's Fellowship, the Breadloaf Fellowship in Poetry and the Stanford Chicano Fellows Fellowship. His publications include thirteen collections of poetry, prose, short stories, young adult novels and picture books for children in the last decade with nineteen books in total His poetry and essays have appeared in both small presses (Bilingual Press and Curbstone) as well as mainstream publishing concerns (University of Arizona Press and Vintage). His works have been translated to Spanish by Mexico's most important publisher, the Fondo de Cultura Economica. Other translations include German and Serbo-Croatian. For his literary endeavors, Herrera has garnered the Ezra Jack Keats Award, the Hungry Mind Award of Distinction, the Americas Award, the Focal Award, the Pura Belpré Honors Award, the Smithsonian Children's Book of the year, the Cooperative Children's Book Center Choice, the IRA Teacher's Choice, the LA Times Book Award Nomination, the Texas Blue Bonnet Nomination, the New York Public Library outstanding book for high school students and two Latino Hall of Fame Poetry Awards. Born in Fowler, California, a small town southeast of Fresno, Herrera traveled with his parents on the seasonal crop circuit, eventually settling in the San Diego area at the age of eight. Upon graduation from San Diego High School in 1967, he was awarded a federal Educational Opportunity Grant and went on to UCLA, earning a B.A. in social anthropology. While at UCLA, Herrera became interested in the performance work of Luis Valdez's El Teatro Campesino, and subsequently formed his own theatre group, Teatro Tolteca. In 1970, with funding from UCLA's Mexican American Center, Herrera traveled to Mexico to study indigenous theatrical expression. The combination of "teatro and the journey through Mexico changed my [his] life forever", and Herrera returned invigorated with a new sense of identity and purpose. His first major work, Rebozos of love we have woven sudor de pueblos on our back, appeared in 1974, and in 1977 he was accepted into Stanford University's graduate program in anthropology, earning an M.A. in 1980. Herrera's restless spirit, however, continued to find more creative outlets in poetry. His Exiles of Desire appeared 1983, a thematic collection exploring the darker side of urban existence, followed in 1987 by Facegames and Akrilika in 1989. With his literary career on the rise, Herrera enrolled in the University of Iowa's Writers Workshop in 1988, attaining the status of fellow with the distinction of Excellence in 1990. Awarded an M.F.A. in creative writing that same year, he joined the Department of Chicano and Latin-American Studies at California State University-Fresno. Throughout the 1990s, Herrera continued to produce collections of poetry in addition to his teaching load of creative writing and theater production. In 1995, Calling The Doves / El Canto De Las Palomas, poetry based on Herrera's childhood experiences in the farming fields of California was released, which brought Herrera into third and fourth grade classrooms across the United States both in print and in person. The fate of indigenous people as they succumb to the pressures of modernization was the subject of his 1997 release Mayan Drifter: Chicano Poet in the Lowlands of America, the result of Herrera's continuing quest to examine identity and culture in the crosscurrents of post-colonial Mesoamerica. He has three forthcoming books and is currently producing "The Twin Tower Songs," a San Joaquin Valley performance memorial on the September 11th tragedy and writing for the PBS television series "American Family." Mr. Herrera is a board member of the Before Columbus American Book Awards Foundation and the California Council for the Humanities. Promoted to Full Professor in 1998, Herrera was elected to the Chair of the Department. Of Chicano and Latin American Studies at California State University-Fresno in 2001.
Note: This biographical sketch includes information gathered from the Dictionary of Literary Biography, Chicano Writers, Second Series, Volume 122; and from Juan Felipe Herrera's most recent curriculum vita, dated March, 2003.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 1999.
Access
There are no restrictions on access.
Mexican American art; American literature -- Mexican American authors; Mexican Americans; Herrera, Juan Felipe
- Series 1: Correspondence
  - Abeyta, Aaron. Poet, student, Colorado State, 3/5/96 (Fax) 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ainsworth, Edward. Invitation to submit work to Prosodia. from editor, Edward Ainsworth. 11 / 14/95 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alameda County Office of Education Correspondence and materials regarding author visit to the Alameda County Office of Education, Hayward Ca 1998 8 pp. [move to corres.] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alarcon, Francisco X. [1] Two Letters from Francisco X. Alarcon. 9/7/90, 10/6/90. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alarcon, Francisco X. [2] Letter from Francisco X. Alarcon regarding presentation at UCSC. 10/3/91. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alexander, Jane. Letter from Jane Alexander, NBA director, 12/17/96 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alicia, Juana. Post card regarding Juana Alicia'a MFA art exhibit. Bay Area. 4/90.[1] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alicia, Juana. Fax Memo from Juana Alicia, SF muralist, 3/4/96 Re: lyrics for her mural at SF airport. Sketches, handwritten words. [2] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Allen, Judith Wesley. Editor. University of Arizona Press. Punk-Half-Panther. Letter. 3/25/98. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alurista. Alurista's self-promotional flyer (poet, friend) 1/23/79 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alvarez, Mollie. Molly Alvarez, poet, friend, daughter of Roberto Alvarez, good friend. 7/17/95. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alvarez, Roberto. Postcard (1988) [1] (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Alvarez, Robert. Letter from my friend Robert Alvarez, regarding sacred corn. 4/17/95. [2] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Alvarez, Robert. Letter & Fronterizo Novel and Excerpt; 125 pages. 7/28/97. [3] (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - American Book Review. Letter. Request for review copy of Love After the Riots. American Book Review. 5/21/96. with reviewers list. 7 pp. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Aparicio, Frances. Letter. Invitation to contribute to anthology. Frances Aparicio, Univ. of Michigan. 10/29/93. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Arenas, Rosie. California Reading and Literature Project. 7/28/98. Contract. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Arroyo, Pedro. 2/16/97 Letter and Article. [1] (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Arroyo, Pedro. Letter. 10/18/97. 91.3FM San Luis Obispo Interview. [2] (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ayer, Amy. Letter. 12/5/97. Windham Area Poetry Project. 2 pages. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Atkins, Laura. Children's Book Press. 6/3/98. 6 pages; Elly Simmons Art Sketches for upcoming book Upside Down Boy. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Baca, Santiago. Correspondence from Jimmy Santiago Baca, poet, screenwriters, 1) letters: 12/15/78, 3/21/79, 4/2/79, 4/9/79, 5/28/79) 2) Flyer; "An Evening with the Arts" (with note from JS Baca stating that this is the first reading since he came out of prison / 11/30/78); 3) an essay: "On Prison's Efficacy & A Proposal for Bettering the System" 4) seven original poems. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Barlow, George. Letter from George Barlow, poet. 4/9/91 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bartridge, Albert Jr. Award Letter from Albert Bartridge Jr., VP, Wells Fargo Bank. Harry C. Mitchell Grant for Summer Arts. Poetry into Performance Workshop. 12/28/95. plus Xerox of check for $5,000. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Befu, Harumi. Letter to Dr. Harunu Befu. Chair of Anthro, Stanford. Regarding re­acceptance into Ph.D. program. 10/8/84. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bell, Marvin. poet, professor, friend, 7/24/89 [1] (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bell, Marvin. Letter from Marvin Bell, poet. 4/26/90. [2] (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bell, Marvin. Letter from Marvin Bell, poet. 2/18/91. [3] (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bell, Marvin. Letter from Marvin Bell regarding job at SIU-Carbondale. 2/2/92. 2 pages.[4] (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Benavides, Nora. Letter from Nora Benavides, Radio Bilingue, Fresno, 5/25/94 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Berc, Shelly. Various: b) Note from Shelly Berc, playwright, professor, Univ. of Iowa, Fall 1989 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bernstein, Jill. Letter from Jill Bernstein, Lit director of AZ. Commission on the Arts. 3/24/97. stationary of Poetasuznanos Poetry Collective event: (1979, Stanford Univ.). (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Betz, Phil. Letter to Phil Betz, Producer, NYC. 11/29/90 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Biddle, Livingston L. re: NEA fellowship, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Biechler, Mike. Memo. Promotion 4/24/92, CSUF; 2 pages. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Biskup, Lisa. Letter from Lisa Biskup, teacher. with student work. 11/28/95. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Blauner, Bob. Letter fro Bob Blauner (Sociologist) regarding essay anthology. 7/24/94. [1] (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Blauner, Bob: Letter with edits on memoir Notes From an Only Child. (2 drafts); 23 pages. 9/6/94 [2] (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Blauner, Bob. Two letters from Bob Blauner re Wife's - Karina - film project and anthology. 9/30/95. [3] (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Blauner, Bob. Letter from Bob Blauner, re: Our Mother's Spirit book. 8/16/97[4] (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Blauner, Bob. 10/3/97. Letter. Oprah show. [5] (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Blauner, Bob. 4/15/98. Letter 2 pages. [6] (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Blauner, Bob. Letter from Bob Blauner, re: Our Mother's Spirit book. 11/28/97 [7] (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Bonnano, David. Letter. Payment for poetry in American Poetry Review. 12/90. Note by editor David Bonanno. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Bourgoise, Phillipe. Partial letter from Phillipe Bourgoise, 1981, upon his return from the border of Honduras, El Salvador, witness to the refugee camps of Salvadorenos run out by the Guardia troops. with one sheet poems by the campesinos also. 1981. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Bovel, Chris. Letter regarding Bisbee Poetry Festival, n.d.[?] (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Brandt, Jenny. Jenny Brandt, Children's Book Press, 1/16/96 (schools contract), 4p. [1] (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Brandt, Jenny. Jenny Brandt. Children's Book Press, updated contract, 3/25/96. 3 pp. [2] (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Bristol, Barbara. Letter from Barbara Bristol, poetry editor, Alfred A. Knopf Inc. NYC. regarding manuscript. 6/12/92. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Broken Moon Press, acknowledging "Frida's Aria" contribution, 7/28/92; and contract for "Indian Journeys" (Mayan Drifter). 7/27/92. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Brown, Larry. Three letters: b) Larry Brown, novelist, 12/7/92. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Bryant, Audry. Letter from Audry Bryant, children's Book editor. David Godine Publisher. 10/31/90. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Buckley, Christopher. 2 letters re anthology project, 10/15/92, 1/29/ 93. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Buckley, Christopher. poet. 12/15/92.[ 2] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Budy, Andrea Hollander. poet 10/31/90. Breadloaf conference buddy.Letter with two fotos (JFH) at conference. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Burciaga, Antonio. Letter from Jose Antonio Burciaga, poet, writer, artist.3/23/92 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Burciaga, Jose Antonio. Note from Jose Antonio Burciaga. Early nineties. With card. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Butler, Johnnella. Univ. of Wash. Seattle. 2/23/93 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cano, Daniel. Letter from Daniel Cano, novelist regarding possible reading at CSU­Fresno with Michele Serros also. 10/3/95. (with vita and reviews, envelope.) [1] (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cano, Daniel Jr. Pacific Development and Marketing. Teatro Brochure; 1 pages; 3/5/98 [2] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cano, Daniel H. Pacific Development and Marketing PDM - 6/15/98. Letter. Workshop Brochure. [3] (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Cardoso, Marcelo. Letter from Marcelo Cardoso, Powerhouse Books, NYC 5/9/97. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Carillo, Juan M. Fax draft of Letter to US Friendship Commission from Juan M. Carrillo, Chief of Grant Program, CAC. Sacramento. Recommendation letter. 6/18/97. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Carter, Trina. Letter from Trina Carter, Librarian, Re: Martin Espada's visit. 3/22/91, with flyer. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Casco, Nathalia. Letter from Nathalia Casco regarding anthology critique. UCBerkeley. 3/10/93. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Castro, Michael. Invitation to submit poetry to River Styx, from Michael Castro, editor. 10/29/90. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Castro, Veronica. Teacher. 1/5/97. Student Letters. 4th grade. Letter and 2 student letters. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Chad/ Chongo#2. Letter from Iowa Writers Workshop buddy, Chad/ Chongo #2. 9/11/90. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Chanda, Justin P. Harper Collins Letter. 4/3/98. Advanced Copies. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Chavez, Denise. Letter from Denise Chavez, playwright, novelist, regarding her legal case against Arte Publico Press. 7/24/95. [1] (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Chavez, Denise. Letter from Denise Chavez regarding Border Book Festival. 2/24/98. [2] (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Children's Book Press. Contract for The Upside Down Boy SF. 10/1/97. with advance check stub. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Chin, Daryl Ngee. Letter from Daryl Ngee Chin, poet, regarding Summer Arts Poetry Anthology. 8/3/95 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Church, Stephanie. Two letters regarding cover foto for Love After the Riots book. Curbstone Press. 9/13/95; 11/3/95. (Xerox of photo). (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Cisneros, Eva. Xerox announcement of CAPAZ organization in LA. with note from Eva Cisneros, a member. 1996. 2 pages. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Cisneros, Sandra. Letter from Sandra Cisneros. 6/9/90. re: writing anthology. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Clark, Kevin. Letter from Kevin Clark, poet. 12/4/90 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Coke, Allison Hedge. Letter from Allison Hedge Coke, poet. 1996. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Conroy, Frank. Letter from Frank Conroy, director, regarding admission into the Iowa Writers' Workshop. 6/24/88. 2 pages. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Contreras, Feliz.(alias the Captain), 4/83. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Contreras, Victor. Letter. 9/29/97. Playwright Competition. Jag Hotel. Nostros. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Cook, Sharon. CATE [California Association of Teachers of English?] Convention. 12/24/96. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Corpi, Lucha. Letter from Lucha Corpi, poet, regarding literary meeting at Jose Antonio Burciaga's house. early eighties. [1] (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Corpi, Lucha. Letter from Lucha Corpi. poet regarding Centro Chicano de Escritores meeting. 4/30/85. [2] (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Coyle, Susan. SF Bay Area Book Council, 9/26/95. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Cox, Stephen. Letter regarding sales and rolyalties from Night Train To Tuxtla, Univ. of Az Press 8 / 12/98 2 pp (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Cullinan, Bee. editor of Wordsong. - 4/30/97 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Cumpian, Carlos. Photo and news articles, 1/23/92. Re: Nezahualcoyotl Poetry Festival in Chicago (5/91). With envelope. Group foto with (front Row/Left to right) Trixudad Sanchez, Sandra Cisneros, Carlos Cortez, (second row) Demetria Martinez, Evangelina Vigil, Raulrsalinas, Rosemary Arenas, (third row) Carlos Cumpian, Luis Rodriguez, Raul Ntho, Ray Gonzalez, JFH and Jose Alvarado. (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Curbstone Press. Contract for Love After the Riots / Poems. Curbstone Press. 10/22/93. 2 pp. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Curbstone Press. Release form 12/17/93; and Service Contract Agreement for Guadalupe Cultural Arts Center, 12/17/93. (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - D'Andrade, Diane. editor. Regarding manuscript rejection. 9/27/91. HBJ.[1] (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - D'Andrade, Diana. Letter from Diana D'Andrade of HBJ publishers. Rejection of manuscripts. 2/26/92 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Daniels, Harry. Letter from Harry Daniels, Associate Dean, regarding Committee service. SIU-Carbondale. 4/15/93. (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Day, Renny. FOCAL Pres. LA Library, Award, 11/18/97.[1] (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Day, Renny. FOCAL. Letter. 2/6/ 98; 2 pages and brochure (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - de Jesus Hernandez, Manuel. ASU, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - de Jesus Hernandez, Manuel 1/16/96 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Deming, Alison. Two letters from Alison Deming, director of U of Az. Poetry Center. Regarding visit. 4/1/93 and 4/27/93 with itinerary. 3 pages. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Devine, Bill. Letter from Bill Devine regarding "Coats for Kids" project. CSUFresno. 12/7/90. (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Deamico, Bernadette. Letter from Bernadette Diamico.Marin Arts Council. 3/31/97. [1] (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Deamico, Bernadette. Letter from Bernadette Diamico.:Marin Arts Council 5/5/97. [2] (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Diaz, Raul. Letter from Raul Diaz, regarding service on the Migrant Education Conference. 3/3/92. (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Don Lucas, Fernando. "Cultural Perspectives" literary magazine, from Fernando Don Lucas, Fairfax High School. 4/24/95. 40 pages. with 2 page letter. (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Dowley, Jennifer. Letter from Jennifer Dowley, NEA. 4/2/97 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Doyle, Judith. Excess Inventory Letter. 7/13/98. (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Dymond, Judy. Letter from Judy Dymond, theatre arts, CSIJ-SB. Regarding Lecture, poetry. 4/25/97 plus my notes on talk (2 sheets). (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Eaton, Deb. Xeroxed memo from Deb Eaton, editor, regarding manuscript ("Eggs for Chico" 16 pages.) with contract and additional info. Scott Foresman Addison Wesley, 7/3/98. [1] (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Eaton, Deb. Editor, 2 letters editor. 1) 8/17/98, 2) 8/4/98. with instruction sheets for stories. (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Eiler, Sharon. Letter from Sharon Eiler, editor of Santa Clara Review regarding acceptance of poems. 12/16/91. (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Ellison, John. Letter from John Ellison, Broken Moon Press, Seattle regarding materials sent. 8/28/91. [1] (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ellison, John. Letter to John Ellison of Broken Moon Press, regarding "Mayan Book" proposal. 3/2/92. [2] (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Ellison, John. Broken Moon Press, 6/ 22/92, 7/7/92. [3] (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ellison, John. a) Letter to publishers of Broken Moon Press, Seattle, regarding breach of Contract 1/13/94 with signed card (Indian Journeys Ms.) b) two letters from John Ellison, publisher Broken Moon Press regarding same Ms.) 9/12/93 and 8/27/93. [4] (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Ellison, John. Last page of letter from John Ellison, Broken Moon Press publisher, early 90's. [5] (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Espada, Martin. poet, 7/8/86 [1] (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Espada, Martin. Three letters from Martin Espada (10/29/90, 11/23/90, 2/16/91). Poet.4p. [2] (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Espada, Martin. Invitation from Martin Espada to submit poetry to Massachusetts Review, 4/24/95. [3] (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Fabre, Genevieve. Letter from Genevieve Fabre, Literary Critic, regarding possible presentations at Paris Conference. 12/20/94. 5 pages with note and envelope. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence. Letter from Lawrence Ferlinghetti regarding poems submitted. 2/12/98. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Ferrara, Geneva. Letter from Geneva Ferrara regarding authors' fair at Martin Luther King Elementary school. 1/30/97.5 pages with envelope. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Fleegle, Andrea. Letter from Andrea Fleegle, editorial assisant at Temple University Press regarding review of Gregory Tanalca's manuscript - Ressentiment. 4/24/98. 2 pages. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Flores, Bill. Xeroxed memo to Departmental Personnel Committee from Bill Flores,Chair of Chicano Studies, regarding Peer Review of my dass. CSU-Fresno. 12/5/90.2 pages. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Flores, Laura. Note from Professor Laura Flores, 10/24/90 [1] (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Flores, Laura. Letter and article, regarding article on JFH, 1/22/93. l0 pp.[2] (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Foster, Sesshu. Letter from poet Sesshu Foster. 2/2/91 [1] (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Foster, Sesshu. poet, writer. Postcard, LA, Ca. mid-90's. [2] (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Francendese, Janet. Letter. Revisions on Mayan Drifter. Janet Francendese, editor at Temple Univ. Press. (with notes by anonymous reviewer). 6/27/96. (Box 3, Folder 18)